Here's another example.
ここにもう1つの例があります
You have an image, and
画像に子猫が含まれていることを
you want your network to say it's an image with a cat in it.
ネットワークに 認識させる必要があります
It doesn't really matter where the cat is, it's still an image with a cat.
子猫の場所が変わっても 画像に子猫が含まれている事実は変わりません
If your network has to learn about kittens in the left corner, and
左隅の子猫と 右隅の子猫を
about kittens in the right corner independently,
別々に学習しなければならない場合 ネットワークは
that's a lot of work that it has to do.
多くの処理を実行する必要があります
How about you telling it, instead explicitly, that objects and images
そこで オブジェクトと画像は 左側にあっても右側にあっても
are largely the same whether they're on the left or on the right of the picture.
ほぼ同じであると 明示的に言い換えてみましょう
That's what's called translation invariance.
これは並進不変と 呼ばれます
Different positions, same kitten.
場所は違っても子猫は同じです
Yet another example.
もう1つ例があります
Imagine you had a long text that talks about kittens.
子猫について述べた 長文があるとします
Does the meaning of kitten change depending on whether it's in the first
子猫の意味は 最初の文と
sentence or in the second one?
2番目の文で異なるでしょうか?
Mostly not, so if you're trying to network on text, maybe you want the part
多くの場合はそうではありません テキストを扱うネットワークを作成する場合は
of the network that learns what a kitten is to be reused every time you see
ネットワークの一部で子猫という語を検出するたびに 子猫の意味を学習し直すのではなく
the word kitten, and not have to re-learn it every time.
その意味が再利用されることを 学習する必要があります
The way you achieve this in your own networks,
独自のネットワークで これを実現するには
is using what's called weight sharing.
重みのシェアを使用します
When you know that two inputs can contain the same kind of information,
2つの入力に 同じ種類の情報が含まれている可能性がある場合は
then you share their weights.
それらの重みをシェアします
And train the weights jointly for those inputs.
さらに重みを 一緒に学習させます
It's a very important idea.
これは非常に重要な考え方です
Statistical invariants, things that don't change on average across time or
統計的不変条件 つまり時間や空間を超えても
space, are everywhere.
ほぼ変化しないものが いたるところにあります
For images,
画像の場合
the idea of weight sharing will get us to study convolutional networks.
重みシェアの考え方は 畳み込みネットワークの検討につながります
For text and sequences in general, it will lead us to embeddings and
一般的な テキストやシーケンスの場合は
recurrent neural networks.
埋め込みと再帰ニューラルネットワークの検討につながります